Kimi Spencer

808.888.9712 hello@kimispencer.com linkedin.com/in/kimispencer

Summary

Front-end engineer UX & Product designer

Key Skills

Responsive web development & design
E-commerce sites
Working with lean, agile teams to design and develop full stack web sites & experiences
Data visualization

Languages

Javascript, ReactJs, AngularJs, HTML5, CSS3/SASS/LESS, PHP, Python, Java/Processing, Webpack, Gulp, Git

Tools

Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, AfterEffects, Premiere Cinema4D VDMX

Education

New York University Interactive Technology Program (ITP) Masters, 2010 - 2012

University of California, Berkeley Political Science Bachelor of Arts, 2003 - 2007

Profile

Hi, I'm Kimi!

I'm a front-end engineer, and user experience + product designer based in NYC. I have over 9 years expertise working in interactive technology. From San Francisco startups to NYC digital agencies; spanning industries from interactive advertising, online magazines/publications, AR games for museum eduction, to high-end fashion. I create digital identity and experiences through concept development, UX & visual design, and creative coding solutions. I also like creating data visualizations, and visuals for live performances/music.

Experience

Lead Front-end Engineer & Interaction Designer

Brainchild.co, The Arrivals, and Onomie — 2014 to present

Brainchild.co is a collection of engineers, operators and designers working on projects spanning from fashion, beauty to health care.

Lead front-end engineer and interaction designer for the <u>The Arrivals</u>, <u>Onomie</u>, and <u>Brainchild.co</u> brand sites since launch. Individually responsible for the creation and implementation of all front-end code and interface design for each brand's respective responsive, cross-platform e-commerce web app. As well as designing and developling monthly interactive campaigns, supporting multiple product launches, and improving the site interface based on A/B studies.

- Co-led conversion of thearrivals.com into a ReactJS application.
- Led the implementation of HTML5, CSS3, client-side Javascript, CSS preprocessing platforms (LESS/SASS), JS task-runners, Git version control.
- Created UX/UI mockups, graphic/web designs, as well as translated mockups into code.
- Assisted with back-end integration and templating.
- Oversaw the launch of multiple successful sites from start to finish under strict deadlines.

Lead Front-end Engineer & Digital Designer Suited Magazine — 2016 to 2017

Summary

Front-end engineer UX & Product designer

Key Skills

Responsive web development & design

E-commerce sites

Working with lean, agile teams to design and develop full stack web sites & experiences Data visualization

Languages

Javascript, ReactJs, AngularJs, HTML5, CSS3/SASS/LESS, PHP, Python, Java/Processing, Webpack, Gulp, Git

Tools

Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, AfterEffects, Premiere Cinema4D VDMX

Education

New York University
Interactive Technology Program
(ITP)

Masters, 2010 - 2012

University of California, Berkeley Political Science Bachelor of Arts, 2003 - 2007 <u>SUITED</u> is a biannual fashion and art publication with a singular mission in mind: to celebrate those who have found what they are well-suited for. Their objective is to showcase independent thinkers passionate about creating work that is at once inspired, influential, and timeless.

Full-stack engineer and UX designer for SUITED Magazine; created a customized CMS driven template design built on top of the Squarespace developer platform. Worked one-on-one with the creative director to translate the print publication into a branded online experience; built visual mockups and interface designs.

Front-end Developer and Product Designer

Bolster - 2013 to 2014

<u>Bolster.us</u> is a web application for home owners & contractors to connect and manage home remodeling projects. Designed and developed a user-facing public website as well as an admin site for users to log in, find their match, upload/share documents & monitor their project's progression. Built with AngularJS using modern web standards.

UX Designer and Front-end Developer

10x Management - 2012 to 2013

10x Management was born from a simple premise: "Find the best contract tech talent and match them with the world's most amazing companies." That was the concept in 2011, when two successful talent managers from the music industry teamed up with a brilliant software engineer to create the world's first tech talent agency. 10x helps match the best contract tech talent with ground-breaking companies, with new talent and companies joining our community every day.

A member of 10x's first class of tech talent in 2012. Freelance UX designer and front-end developer.

Product Designer and Front-end Developer

+plusign - 2012 to 2013

<u>+plusign</u> is an award-winning creative studio that does branding, digital, and design. Product designer and Front-end web developer for multiple client projects spanning real-estate, beauty, and the arts.

Experience Design Intern

R/GA - 2011

Developed detailed wireframes and collaborated in the redesign of Verizon Wireless in-store touch screen experiences. Designed and rapidly prototyped a mobile application for MasterCard's and the High Line Park of NYC's Priceless Cities campaign. Created user journeys, as well as filmed and edited

Summary

Front-end engineer UX & Product designer

Key Skills

Responsive web development & design
E-commerce sites
Working with lean, agile teams to design and develop full stack web sites & experiences
Data visualization

Languages

Javascript, ReactJs, AngularJs, HTML5, CSS3/SASS/LESS, PHP, Python, Java/Processing, Webpack, Gulp, Git

Tools

Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, AfterEffects, Premiere Cinema4D VDMX

Education

New York University Interactive Technology Program (ITP) Masters, 2010 - 2012

University of California, Berkeley Political Science Bachelor of Arts, 2003 - 2007 corresponding concept videos. Participated in the R/GA Data Visualization Incubator. Mined, analyzed and programmed a series of information graphics of Verizon's service networks for the creative team to better understand customer flows and touch points of the Verizon brand experience. rga.com

Project Manager and Web/Graphic Designer Guide by Cell — 2008-2010

Guide by Cell develops mobile engagement solutions to support audiotours, games and other location based interactions for museums and other cultural institutions.

Designed, user tested, and launched interactive mobile applications and media content for over 300 museums and exhibitions. Participated in the development of <u>Ghosts of a Chance</u> the first Augmented Reality Game (ARG) played at the Smithsonian Museum of American Art. Created wireframes, developed mobile games and location-based narratives.